[
    {
        "question": "Atomic mass of Nitrogen is",
        "options": [
            "10",
            "12",
            "14",
            "16"
        ],
        "answer": 3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Atomic mass of Hydrogen is",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "1",
            "4"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Valence shell of an element has 6 electron its valency is.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "6",
            "1"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Neither gained nor lost during chemical reaction.",
        "options": [
            "Atomic number",
            "Matter",
            "Mole",
            "Electrons"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Mass of 1 mole of carbon atom is",
        "options": [
            "12 grams",
            "24 grams",
            "6 grams",
            "36 grams"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The symbol of Helium is",
        "options": [
            "He",
            "H",
            "Na",
            "K"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Atomic mass of calcium is.",
        "options": [
            "40",
            "35.5",
            "12",
            "14"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "The Symbol N is used to denote.",
        "options": [
            "Avogadro's number",
            "Mass number",
            "Atomic radius"        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Very tiny particles are",
        "options": [
            "Molecule",
            "Radical",
            "Element",
            "Atom"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The valency of the element is 2 with electronic configuration.",
        "options": [
            "2, 6",
            "2, 8",
            "2, 1",
            "2, 4"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "State the valency of Cu   in CuSO .",
        "options": [
            "14",
            "4",
            "3",
            "2"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The mass of 0.5 mole of Nitrogen gas is",
        "options": [
            "7 grams",
            "14  grams",
            "21  grams",
            "18  grams"
        ],
        "answer": 2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Two or More element combine to form a.",
        "options": [
            "Atom",
            "Compound",
            "The avogadro’s number",
            "Atomic mass"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "144 make ............... grass.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "3",
            "1"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The mass of 2 moles of carbon is",
        "options": [
            "36 grams",
            "12 grams",
            "24 grams",
            " 48 grams"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1961 which atom was selected as the reference atom.",
        "options": [
            "Hydrogen",
            "Oxygen",
            "Carbon",
            "Nitrogen"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": " 6.022 × 10 is called.",
        "options": [
            "Avogadro’s number",
            "Molecular Mass",
            "Atomic number",
            "Atomic mass"
        ],
        "answer": 1 
    },
    {
        "question": "14 is atomic mass of",
        "options": [
            "Carbon",
            "Oxygen",
            "Nitrogen",
            "Hydrogen"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Molecular formula of water is",
        "options": [
            "CO2",
            "NH3",
            "H2O",
            "CI2"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is positively charged particle ?",
        "options": [
            "Proton",
            "Neutron",
            "Electron",
            "Atom"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The mass of 1 mole of Nitrogen gas is",
        "options": [
            "7 grams",
            "14 grams",
            "28 grams"        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Carbon atom was selected as the reference atom in which year.",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1980",
            "1965",
            "1972"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Valency of carbon is",
        "options": [
            "4",
            "2",
            "3",
            "1"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Symbol of boron",
        "options": [
            "Ca",
            "B",
            "Be",
            "n"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    }
]